Hey, how's it going guys?
John here. I hope y'all are having an amazing month.
I know it's been a while since I've released any, uh,
new trainings, but, uh, one thing that I wanted
to go over today was how I actually track ads, um,
as a video production company,
even though we don't run the ads ourselves, um,
it's really important that when, whether you're a freelancer
or an agency or you're a video production company,
that you are tracking, uh, all the ads
that you are launching,
and if you've been on LinkedIn,
if you follow other creative, uh, strategists
and such, such, you'll find that everybody has kind
of a different system for this.
And this is what has worked for me.
It's not the perfect system,
but it allows me, uh, granularity
and, um, specificity in terms of
what is moving the needle, um, in terms of creative, um,
especially if I'm not in the actual ad accounts myself.
So this is, um, this is a tool called Airtable,
and essentially it's very similar to Google Sheets.
There is a learning curve to it.
It's, um, it's, whoops, I just spilled my, my drink.
Um, uh, it's, it's like Google, Google Sheets on steroids,
and I prefer it because the sorting
and filtering of the data
is a lot more robust than let's say, um, Google Sheets.
And so I'll just do a quick
overview of what this looks like.
Um, so for example, anytime I have a new creative, um, one
of the key things that I'm testing
is we're testing a general style, obviously kind
of working backwards from what has worked.
So for this particular client and,
and project, um, mashups have been the style of edits
that I've been producing for them.
And so I always have like an ad name
naming convention for it.
And then there's some automations here.
But what, um,
what this all means is basically like this is the test
number, um, for the month,
and then this is the phase in which we are
testing the creative.
So we're actually testing the creative itself
and then the variable.
So in here I have like different variables.
I have a scroll stop
or text overlay thumbnail, headline ad style.
You know, there's, there's different
variables that you want to test.
Um, in order to like, just for your own sake,
get a track record of previous learnings and previous tests.
Because as a performance
creative strategist slash marketer slash producer, you know,
you always want to know what is moving the needle.
And I think this is the one thing
that right now is missing in the course,
and in the program is just overall like post, um,
post testing, right?
And this is, this can get really, like, really hairy,
especially if you're not not into the accounts.
And I'm speaking directly to video editors and,
and freelancers who aren't necessarily doing this right now,
um, because you don't have an agency
or you're not a creative strategist,
but I'm, I'm really urging those who are video editors
to be, to begin learning how to do this.
And you don't need this big, crazy thing.
Um, in Airtable, I would share it with you,
but I just don't know how right now, but I'll figure it out.
But, you know, u utilizing Google Sheets
is a great place to start.
And if you track your creatives here
and just kind of use the same
format, I'll go through it again.
I'm sorry, I'm jumping around.
I just want to really share the importance of doing this.
Then you'll, you can have a track record of what you've,
what you've done in the past and what moved the needle.
All right? So obviously we had the test variable.
And this is really important to, to remember
that when you're testing, like you're not just testing
random stuff and you're testing things based off
of a hypothesis and,
and based off of what's already working right?
In the beginning, yeah, it might be kind of random,
but as you get more data, then you can kind of,
you can build on what the data's telling you.
So for example, if it's a,
if it's a headline that works really well.
So going back to this, we have a couple variables here.
We have the headline, which is how to, how
to get tipsy without the booze.
Like, this has just worked really well for the brand.
And so there's no reason to kind of like, I mean, there is,
you can still innovate on it, but there's no reason to go
and test like, wild things
that wouldn't necessarily be aligned.
'cause we already got the data and know that this works.
Um, and then the next thing that I track actually,
that I don't know how many people are doing this,
but I actually track the video hooks themselves, okay?
So I will write down what the video hook was,
and then I'll include a thumbnail of it.
So this kind of gives me perspective on, okay, like
reaction hooks worked really, really well for this brand.
And so that kind of information, if I'm going
through the raw footage, like I know I'm looking
for reactions or when they work with UGC creators,
like they're telling them, Hey,
we need more reactions from you, right?
So it, it goes full circle.
And I believe as a, as a creative, like,
I think the next step to being a video editor is being a
video editor and creative strategist that can do all in one
because like I said, in, in the training
and course, like if you're just a video editor
and you're just putting together the parts
without really understanding the strategy
or the reason why something worked,
then I think you're gonna be left behind.
And somebody did mention that in the, the course,
or I'm sorry, in the community recently.
And so, like, everyone has their own system for this.
And I don't wanna say that mine's perfect by any means,
but this has allowed me like a,
a proper naming convention as well.
So these are all formulas that I've created.
Um, so I know like, okay, scroll stopper 89
and headline 56, were the, were the winning ones, right?
And I'm testing one variable at a time,
and this just allows me a lot more clarity and specificity.
So for me, let's say
I launched these ads and for example,
we just launched these ads and it's one style
and I just changed the hook, right?
But they're, they're a little bit different from each other
in terms of the actual scroll stoppers themselves.
Um, but next
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna follow up in a couple days
with the, with the brand
and the agency that I'm working with,
and I'm just gonna ask for data.
Um, I don't need so much as a creative in terms of like,
what, like, I, like, it's nice to get like the hook rate
and the, the click the rate, all that stuff is nice.
But, um, what I'm really looking
for is like, is it converting or not?
Yes or no? And if it's not converting, um,
what can we do next, right?
And so out of these, these variations,
we're gonna look at some of the soft metrics
and compare them
and see which ones are either getting really good engagement
and not sales, or the ones
that are just completely not working at all,
or the ones that are, you know, working.
'cause surprisingly, like sometimes your,
your soft metrics could be crap,
but it could be a really profitable ad.
So it really just depends.
But at the end of the day, sales is what matters, right?
So I'll just go in here
and I'll just rank these like, okay,
this one was like a wand.
This one was like a a two,
and by the way, this is like not quantitative
or qualitative whatsoever.
I'm just like, these are just little markers for me.
And you know, I'm not a data guy, so I don't like
to like sit there and stare at it,
but I, I do need this information
to move forward to the next stage.
And so let's say like this one was, was the hook, right?
Um, and so what we'll do is just,
we'll expand on that, right?
So we, with this particular creative,
we were just really testing one message and just hooks.
Um, now for the second iteration, like they wanted
to test a different angle, which would be like a DHD angle.
So, you know, I would create a new ad name
and I would call it like, uh, SB
a DHD one.
And then from here, um, I would label the test,
test two, put this into creative testing,
and then I'm gonna be te testing the scroll
stopper plus the ad style.
Um, and then from here, you know, we'd come up with,
with hooks right here, like how this solved my A DHD.
We're gonna be very careful with the claims here.
And then for the video hook, I'm going
to create a new record.
And so if this is your first time seeing Airtable,
I'm sure it's gonna be like, really confusing.
But, um, I'm just gonna walk through it really quick.
Um, so like, person struggling
and I'm basically taking screenshots from my timeline
and then putting 'em in here struggling to focus.
All right? So, and then let's say for example, you know,
I took a screenshot there.
Um, let me just use this one as, 'cause I have a image,
but I'll put it into the thumbnail.
And I just like the visual aspect of things.
And again, I know there's other tools.
I think there's, um, motion, which is one of them
that like performance creators, strategists use.
Again, I'm not one of those, I don't wanna be on those.
Um, but this becomes one variation, right?
And then if I just want to create a new variation,
I'll just duplicate this
and I'll change these, um, these parameters.
So whether it's a headline or a hook, um,
and yeah, that's basically like my, my tracking process.
And it's not perfect, but it is what it is.
And if you guys want, like,
if you want like a more in depth like setup on how to, how
to set this up yourself, I might be able
to put something together in Google Sheets
or share this entire thing with you.
And then I, yeah, I don't wanna like share it
because I don't wanna like, uh,
it's like client information obviously,
but maybe I can make a fake one
or like a, I can duplicate it
and make it as like a stock one
and then you guys can, can pull from it.
So anyways, I hope that's helpful.
I know it's a little all over the place,
but I wanted to share something with you guys, um,
in the meantime since we weren't able
to jump on a call today.
Anyways, appreciate you all and hope you all are doing good.
We're gonna be, um, we're a little
behind on sharing some templates,
but we are getting those sent out today.
So look forward to that in your email.
And yeah, I'll see you guys soon.